Dzvinka Mytsyk

Email: <u>dzvinka.mytsyk@gmail.com</u>

Skype: dzvenyslava.mytsyk Residence: Berlin, Germany

LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/dzvinkamytsyk

Mobile: +49 157 386 46 321

Senior Business Analyst, Product Owner

I am highly professional IT business analyst with experience across different domains. I have successful experience as a Product Owner and in leading a software development team as Scrum Master and Project Manager. I am very passionate about agile methodologies and software development best practices.

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Lean, Scrum and Agile

Version control

Operation systems

Spoken languages

Product Discovery

Software requirements management

Product Backlog management

Software life cycle management

Strong analytical skills

SKILLS AND QUALIFICATIONS	
Product Management	Product backlog management, Product Vision, Product Road-map, Personas, Scenarios, Storyboarding, A/B testing, MVP and MMP, MVP metrics
UX and UI	Balsamiq, CanvasFlip, InVision, Proto.io, MS Visio, Draw.io, Gliffy UX principles, Lean UX, Product Discovery, Usability testing
Business Analysis	User Story Mapping, Requirements elicitation, documentation and management
Domain experience	Investment banking; Search optimization; Natural Language Processing; Travel; Email marketing;
Software Development	SQL, HTML5, CSS3, JSON, XML, XSLT JavaScript / Jquery, Java - basic skills
Methodologies	Agile, Lean, XP, Scrum, Kanban, Lean Startup
Project Management	Trello, JIRA, Confluence, MS Project, OKRs
Databases	PostgreSQL, MySQL, Oracle - understanding and ability to create complex DB schemas , hands on as user
Frameworks	Understanding of J2EE technologies, REST, micro-services

English – fluent, Ukrainian – native, Russian – bilingual, Polish – intermediate, French and German – novice

Git, GutHub, Subversion

Microsoft Windows, Linux

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Ringier AG — Berlin, Germany

April 2014 - June 2014

<u>Freelance Project Manager – EMS migration project</u>

Customer: Internal Ringier project

Project: migrating Ringier websites from existing legacy EMS systems to SailThru EMS

Role: coordinate multi-functional teams from 7 countries in Asia and Africa: marketing, creative and IT.

Key results:

Marketing specification for 10+ websites prepared

- IT scope defined and WBS prepared
- Creative scope defined and delivered

<u>Epam Systems</u> (NYSE: EPAM) — Budapest, Hungary & Kyiv, Ukraine

August 2006 - July 2013

One of the biggest outsourcing software services and solutions providers from Central and Eastern Europe. EPAM provides expert consulting, development, testing, support and infrastructure services to many of the world's leading organizations like Barclays Capital, UBS, Boeing, etc. Distributed delivery model includes mix of Onshore/NearShore and Offshore approaches.

<u>Search Engine Analyst, Scrum Mater — WK project</u>

Customer: Wolters Kluwer

Project: multinational document search platform (based on Microsoft Fast search engine).

Role: search engine configuration, optimization and trouble shooting; new search requirements implementation and new platform releases roll-outs; Agile process coordination.

Key results:

- · Several successful releases of search engine for multi-lingual international deployments
- Innovative ideas accepted by customers: UI redesign, documentation process improvement, etc.

Senior Business Analyst, deputy Product Owner - FuSA project

Customer: UBS AG

Project: Bank's internal software for settlements and confirmations processing

Role: requirements clarification and documentation, deputy Product Owner on several sub-projects, Scrum Master on several iterations, xsd and xslt development, sql scripting, test cases and test scenarios creation, taking part in QA process.

Key results:

- Successful implementation and deployment of commodities derivatives trades processing
- Successful CDS trade processing re-engineering and support

Project Manager, Business Analyst - CMP project

Customer: Clarabridge

Project: Text mining engine and natural language processing

Role: distributed team management, QA management, negotiations with customers, product strategy development and execution control; business processes analysis; software requirements writing.

Key results:

- Multiple successful releases of natural language processing module
- · Implementation and deployment of QA on-line monitoring system

<u>Project Manager / Business Analyst — Cactus System</u>

Customer: EPAM Systems

Project: Internal tool for contractor employees accounting process

Role: distributed team management (4 offices, up to 30 team members); project planning, progress monitoring and control; entire project's documentation review; negotiations with customers and business processes analysis; software requirements writing; communication with development and testing teams.

Key results:

- Managing project from the start, creating a team, implementing Scrum processes
- Successful releases and deployment of several versions of the system for EPAM's internal accounting department

Business Analyst — Phoenix System re-engineering

Project: re-engineering of existing system for health insurance company in USA

Role: negotiations with customers and business processes analysis; software requirements writing; communication with development and testing teams.

Key results:

· Creating comprehensive requirements set (including wire-frames) for the first phase of re-engineering

Ukrainian Mobile Communications — Kyiv, Ukraine (now MTS Ukraine)

November 2005 - June 2006

One of the largest mobile operator in Ukraine. In 1993, it was the first company to introduce mobile (cellular) services in Ukraine. As of today, Ukrainian MTS network support various value-added services based on GPRS / EGPRS / EDGE and SMS / WAP / MMS / USSD. MTS is the only BlackBerry service provider in Ukraine and is also a service provider of WiFi hotspots, mainly in large cities and airports.

Project Coordinator - "Coverage complaints processing database"

Role: project planning; software requirements analysis; execution, monitoring and control; negotiation with stakeholders.

Key results:

- Created a full process description of mobile coverage complaints processing.
- Successful release, deployment and maintenance of the overage complaints DB.

Mirasoft-Group Corp — Kyiv, Ukraine

June 2004 - October 2005

Mirasoft is a Ukrainian provider of software outsourcing services. Mirasoft specializes in the development of business administration tools, document management and work-flow solutions and electronic medical systems has industry-specific expertise in several business sectors, including financial, technology, telecom and health-care.

<u>Project Manager – IPLocks Automated Test System Development</u>

Project: Creating new QA-automation software solution

Role: project planning; execution, monitoring and control; risk management; communication with customer and internal communication; reporting; quality planning, assurance and control; human resource management, team development, coaching & trainings & hiring, project processes development and deployment.

Key results:

- Successful prototype creation which retained a new customer
- · Released several versions of QA-automation software
- Increased the team from initial 2 people to 10-15 (in different phases)

Business processes Analyst - CMMI Deployment

Project: CMMI processes deployment throughout the company, CMMI level 3 certification *Role*: CMMI training participation, organizational and project processes development and deployment, internal processes trainings creation and presentation.

Key results:

- 3 CMMI processes trainings prepared and delivered
- 3 CMMI processes tailored and deployed into projects life-cycle

Business Analyst — Top Dog

Project: travel web-service application development – hotel booking, planes tickets, car rental *Role*: software requirements specification analysis, design documents creation, technical specification preparation, QA, project processes development and deployment.

Key results:

• Successful integration of 5 service providers into the system (specification, QA coordination, acceptance)

ICC Company - Kyiv, Ukraine

October 2003 - May 2004

ICC – web-development company, part of large Ukrainian publishing house "SoftPress". Main purpose – create and support web-sites of published magazines.

Software Developer - multiple web-projects

Project: create and support web-sites of published magazines

Role: database structure development, design development, php code, sql scripts.

EDUCATION

National University of "Kyiv-Mohyla Academy" — Kyiv, Ukraine

Bachelor's degree in Computer Science

1999 - 2003

Secondary School #47 - Lviv, Ukraine

Secondary education completed with the Gold Medal for High Honors

1988 - 1999